Inventory of the Grani articles submitted for publication
Hoover Institution Archives
Grani articles submitted for publication
1955-2002
2007C32
Hoover Institution Archives
13 manuscript boxes (3.2 linear feet)
Relates to Russian literature.
Grani.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2007.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Russian émigré literary journal published in Frankfurt, Germany.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection contains novels, poems, and articles submitted by authors for publication in magazine Grani, related to political, social and economic conditions in the Soviet Union and post -Soviet Union. Records are arranged as originally received from the organization.
Russia--Emigration and immigration.; Russian literature.; Russian periodicals.
- "Koshka v dome," Galina Kraeva (Dzhygashvili), circa 2000 (Box 1: 1)
- Poems by Porokhin Sergei, 2000 (Box 1: 2)
- "Konstantin Paustovskii-volshebnik slova," Liudmila Matthews, circa 2000 (Box 1: 3)
- "U Tavrii v plenu," Aleksandr Liusyi, circa 2000 (Box 1: 4)
- "Filmor-reka zhizni," Petr Balakshin, circa 1995 (Box 1: 5)
- "O Viacheslave Ivanove," Viktor Troitskii, circa 2000 (Box 1: 6)
- "Rossiia-Feniks," Dmitrii Shliapentokh, 1999 (Box 1: 7)
- "Sumerechnaia zona," Aleksei Rafiev, circa 2000 (Box 1: 8)
- "Slovo o pisateliakh," Arkadii Bartov, circa 2000 (Box 1: 9)
- Poems by Natal'ia Riabinina, 2000 (Box 1: 10)
- "Stranitsy istorii razvedchestva-skautizma, Rostislav Polchaninov, 2000 (Box 1: 11)
- "Pominnoe slovo," Evgenii Danilov, 1989-1992 (Box 1: 12)
- Poems by Anatolii Iukhimenko, circa 2000 (Box 1: 13)
- Poems by Andrei Griaznov, circa 2000 (Box 1: 14)
- "Budni tridtsat' sed'mogo goda," Naum Korzhavin, circa 1995 (Box 1: 15)
- "Muzyka," Vasilii Drobot, circa 1995 (Box 1: 16)
- "Iz knigi nichtozhestv," Anatolii Iukhimenko, citca 2000 (Box 1: 17)
- "Poslednii mokryi sneg," Ritalii Zaslavskii, 1980-1990 (Box 1: 18)
- O knige Petra Grigorenko "V podvale mozhno vstretit' tol'ko kryc," by Naum Korzhavin, circa1991 (Box 1: 19)
- "Mir na rasstoianii vystrela," Aleksandr Zorin, circa1995 (Box 1: 20)
- "Tam pel Mitskevich vdokhnovennyi," Vladimir Korobov, circa 1998 (Box 1: 21)
- "U bezdny na kraiu," Gennadii Frolov, circa 1995 (Box 1: 22)
- "Glaznoe iabloko," Nikita Ianev, 2000 (Box 1: 23)
- "Pis'mo," Vladimir Korobov, circa 1995 (Box 1: 24)
- "Filosof iz Sumposada," Iurii Linnik, circa 1995 (Box 1: 25)
- "Svetlye nochi nashikh nadezhd," Viktor Govorkov, circa 1990 (Box 1: 26)
- "Paranoidal'nyi srez," Irina Polishchuk, circa 1995 (Box 1: 27)
- "Besplodie pervoi stepeni," Irina Polishchuk, circa1995 (Box 1: 28)
- "Spasibo tovarishchu Stalinu," Osip Spasov (Box 1: 29)
- "Strakh dvadtsatiletnei davnosti," Vladimir Batshev, circa 1990 (Box 1: 30)
- "Parapsikhologiia, sovremennoe sostoianie i puti v budushchee," Vladimir Flerov, 1998 (Box 1: 31)
- "Rossiia i Zapad glazami generala-dissidenta, " Boris Sokolov, circa 1997
- Epigrammy, Aleksandr Sabilev, 1996 (Box 1: 32)
- "Kogda my v Rossiiu vernemsia," Dmitirii Vashchenko, 2000 (Box 1: 33)
- "Vdali siiaiushchuiu tainu..," Marina Tumanova, 1997 (Box 1: 34)
- "Moskva," Igor Petrov, 1994
- "Malen'kii Motsart," Nina Gracheva, circa1995 (Box 1: 36)
- "U bezdny na samom kraiu," Gennadii Frolov, circa 1995 (Box 1: 37)
- "Poslednii roman pravoslaviia, " Marina i Evgenii Chernovitovy, 1998 (Box 1: 38)
- "Poet-romantik Edgar Allan Po," Valentina Senkevich, circa 1995 (Box 1: 39)
- "Byvaiut strannye sblizhen'ia," Boris Sokolov, 1997 (Box 1: 40)
- "Pamiati Bulata Okudzhavy," Anna Kotova, 1997 (Box 1: 41)
- "Zagadochnaia Rus' s ubitymi tsariami," Svetlana Solozhenkina, circa 1995 (Box 1: 42)
- "Rossiia i zapad: v teni velikogo Inkvizitora," Boris Sokolov, circa 1995 (Box 1: 43)
- "Sneg nad Rossiei. Chto tam za etim snegom?" Iurii Levitanskii, circa 1995 (Box 2: 1)
- "Istoriia tiflisskogo al'boma Nikolaia Gumileva," Gleb Vasil'ev and Galina Nikitina, 1997 (Box 2: 2)
- "Nabokov prinadlezhit...," Mikhail Laikov, circa 1995 (Box 2 :3)
- "Put' dalekii do Tippereri...," Natal'ia Bragina, circa 1995 (Box 1: 4)
- "Kitaets", "Man'ka," Vladimir Korobov, circa 1995 (Box 1: 5)
- "Otnoshehiia Zapada i Vostoka- v nastoiashchem i budushchem," Pitirim Sorokin, 1965 (Box 2: 6)
- "Rossiia i Zapad glazami generala-dissidenta," Boris Sokolov, circa 1997 (Box 2: 7)
- "Trudnyi" podrostok (vospominaniia o shkol'nykh godakh Andreia Tarkovskogo)," Iurii Kochevrin, 1997 (Box 2: 8)
- "Stan' Vifleemskoiu zvezdoi," Nikolai Morshen, circa 1995 (Box 2: 9)
- "Moi neokonchennyi romans," Grigorii Iaremenko, circa 2000 (Box 2: 10)
- "Mir vse ravno kachaetsia na grani," Mark Sergeev, circa 2000 (Box 2: 11)
- "Taina Viktora Tsoia", circa 1995 (Box 2: 12)
- "Koshchuna o zhenstve," Nag Sternin, circa 1995 (Box 2: 13)
- "Baron fon Grevenits, Lidiia Golovkova, circa 1995 (Box 2: 14)
- "Russkie tserkvi v Evrope," Sviatoslav Zabelin, 1995 (Box 2: 15)
- "Femistokl, syn Neokla," Dmitrii Shliapentokh, circa 2000 (Box 2: 16)
- "Zhuan," Dmitrii Shliapentokh, circa 2000 (Box 2: 17)
- "Polkovnik Elizar," Dmitrii Shliapentokh, 2001 (Box 2: 18)
- Poems, Dmitrii Sliapentokh, 1979-1991 (Box 2: 19)
- "Oktiabr'skii sad," Dmitrii Vetvin, 2000 (Box 2: 20)
- "Dukhovnyi mir i ikonopos' inokini Ioanny, " G. Popv, 1998 (Box 2: 21)
- "Vladimir Sorokin mezhdy Vostokom i Zapadom," Boris Sokolov, circa 1995 (Box 2: 22)
- "Stalinskii fond," Nag Sternin, circa 1995 (Box 2: 23)
- "Mify o Rossii i dukh natzii," Aleksandr Gorianin, circa 1995 (Box 2: 25)
- " O vere i neverii," Gennadii Rossosh, circa 2000 (Box 2: 25)
- "Al'ter ego," Viktor Togo, 1996 (Box 2: 26)
- "Voina, sem'ia, evakuatsiia," Gedda Shor, 1997 (Box 2: 27)
- "Siniavskii," Vladimir Batshev, circa 1995 (Box 2: 28)
- "Chas Evropy," Andrei Novikov, circa 1995 (Box 2: 29)
- "Otkuda vy vziali chto Chechnia chast' Rossii?" Andrei Novikov, circa 1995 (Box 2: 30)
- "Lev Tolstoi i Dostoevskii. Vechnye sputniki," Dmitrii Merezhkovskii, circa 1995 (Box 3: 1)
- "K 80-letiiu so dnia rozhdeniia Leona Tooma," Anna Toom, circa 1969 (Box 3: 2)
- "Kak eto bylo," Pavel Barto, 1980 (Box 3: 3)
- "Put' na vershinu gory," Vadim Iusov, 1990 (Box 3: 4)
- "Organicheskii tragizm golosa i slova ( o pesniakh Aleksandra Zhdanova)," Konstantin Iusupov, 2001 (Box 3: 5)
- Stikhi, Anna, 1997-2000 (Box 3: 6)
- "Konets legendy," P. Muraviev, circa 1990 (Box 3: 7)
- "Spisok ob"emnykh materialov iz arkhiva samizdata", 1986 (Box 3: 8)
- "Zaveshchanie," Mikhail Shangin, 1999 (Box 3 " 9)
- "Nad propast'iu v Moskve i mire," Vladimir Lazarev, 1988-2000 (Box 3: 10)
- "Moskovskie rasstrely," Lidiia Golovkova, 2000 (Box 3: 11)
- "Moi avgust," Natal'ia Khatkina, 1999 (Box 3: 12)
- "Grot," Natal'ia Khatkina, 1999 (Box 3: 13)
- "Listopad," Vladimir Rafeenko, circa 1994 (Box 3: 14)
- "Blok-post," Vladimir Rafeenko, circa 2000 (Box 3: 15)
- "Razgadka," Evgenii Bogat, circa 1995 (Box 3: 16)
- "Diagnosis dubitus," Ian Torchinskii, circa 2000 (Box 3: 17)
- "Zagneta," Mikhail Shangin, circa 1985 (Box 3: 18)
- Stkhi, Valerii Nesterov, circa 2000 (Box 3: 19)
- "Krest," Ian Torchiinskii, circa 2000 (Box 3: 20)
- "Situatsia," Ian Torchinskii, circa 2000 (Box 3: 21)
- "Sodruzhestvo "Posev" v dvukh stolitsakh", 1999 (Box 3: 22)
- "Chto ia pomniu o Eliseevykh," Nina Landes, circa 2000 (Box 3: 23)
- "Chernye rozy," Zinovii Vinokurov, undated (Box 3 :24)
- "Ot shchedrigi serdtsa," Anastasiia Tsvetaeva, 1996-1999 (Box 3: 25)
- "Stikhi zarubezhnykh poetov, zhivushchikh v SShA,' Oleg Il'inskii, circa 2000 (Box 3: 26)
- O starinnykh russkikh knigakh, Boris Rozenfel'd, undated (Box 4: 1)
- Iz arkhiva bibliofila, Boris Rozenfel'd, undated (Box 4: 2)
- "Diptikh," Svetlana Zagotova, circa 1995 (Box 4: 3)
- "Solovki," Nikita Ianev, 2000 (Box 4: 4)
- "Morskaia bezdna," Sergei Porokhin, 2000 (Box 4: 5)
- "Kratkaia kniga proshchanii," Vladimir Rafeenko, circa 2000 (Box 4: 6)
- "Informatsionnoe pis'mo o rezul'tatakh ugolovnogo rassledovaniia v otnoshenii proizvoditelei programm "Intellekt","A. V. Gol'tsov, 2001 (Box 4: 7)
- "Eshche raz o "russkoi idee"," Sergei Utekhin, circa 2000 (Box 4: 8)
- "Kamchatka," Ida Vodiakova, 1998 (Box 4: 9)
- Vstrecha rossiiskikh i chechenskikh deputatov v Magace, 2000 (Box 4: 10)
- "Dvoinoi publ'," Aken Ibragimov, 1998 (Box 4: 11)
- "Russkie vystupili za nezavisimost' Ichkerii," apeal, 2000 (Box 4: 12)
- "Ukrainskii vopros," Andrei Dikii, 1956 (Box 4: 13)
- "Novyi rossiiskii mortirologii," Preosviashchennyi Tikhon, Episkop Kirillovskii, 1981 (Box 4: 14)
- Stikhi, Ekaterina Kudriavtseva, 1999 (Box 4: 15)
- "Iz knigi chetverostishii," Ritalii Zaslavskii, circa 1980 (Box 4: 16)
- "Elitarnyi sindrom," Liudmila Sal'nikova i Sergei Barsukov, circa 1990 (Box 4: 17)
- "Reshkiny," Aleksandr Selisskii, 2000 (Box 4: 18)
- "Ekaterina III." Nikolai Denisov, undated (Box 4 :19)
- "Svoi Adrian," Dar'ia Valikova, circa 1980 (Box 4: 20)
- "Rodina," Rimma Kazakova, circa 1980 (Box 4: 21)
- "Iarmarka v Sokol'nikakh" Fridrikha Neznanskogo", 1985 (Box 4: 22)
- "Puteshestvie," Lazar' Shereshevskii, 1994 (Box 4: 23)
- "Zagadochnaia Rus' s ubitymi tsariami," Svetlana Solozhenkina, circa 1980 (Box 4: 24)
- "Pust," Mikhail Piss'mennyi, circa 1990 (Box 4: 25)
- Stikhi, Mikhail Zorin, circa 1980 (Box 4: 26)
- "Uchenyi za barankoi," Mark Popovskii, 1997 (Box 4: 27)
- "Dezhurstvo ili roman s krysoi," Boris Vul'fovich, 1998 (Box 4: 28)
- Stikhi poetov russkogo zarubezh'ia, 1996 (Box 4: 1996)
- "Rossiia i Zapad: v teni velikogo inkvizitora," Boris Sokolov, 1997 (Box 4: 30)
- "Viazemskii al'manakh" no.1, 1999 (Box 4: 31)
- "Gospoda ofitsery," Nikolai Turbin, 1965 (Box 4: 32)
- "V vorovskoi voron'ei stolitse," Irina Legkaia, 1997 (Box 4: 33)
- "Moi otets," Levon Khechoian, circa 1985 (Box 4: 1985)
- "V. V. Bychkov. "Estetika ottsov tserkvi. Apologety," Viktor Obukhov, circa 1995 (Box 4: 35)
- "Bozhestvennaia komediia," Dante, translation, S. Aidinian, circa 1980 (Box 4: 36)
- "Sotsial'nye liki sovremennoi Rossii-utopicheskie i nastoiashchie," Liudmila Sal'nikova i Sergei Barsukov, circa 1990 (Box 4: 37)
- "Preemstvennost' ili razryv?" Arkadii Bartov, circa 1990 (Box 4: 38)
- "Iz rasskazov kapitana Paba," Nag Sternin, circa 1990 (Box 5: 1)
- "Podsvechnik Alladina," Nag Sternin, circa 1990 (Box 5: 2)
- "Metamotfoza," Viktor Togo, 1978-1998 (Box 5: 3)
- "Lazar' Gindin: portret vracha n afone dvukh vekov, Viktor Krotov, circa 2000 (Box 5: 4)
- "Trinom Likony," Galina Dzhugashvili, circa 1990 (Box 5: 5)
- Stikhi, Valadimir Korobov, circa 1985 (Box 5: 6)
- "Akh, moi milyi Andersen," Elena Kuznetsova, 1998 (Box 5: 7)
- "Tramvainaia ostanovka u osennego parka," Elena-Mariia Romanushko, 1988 (Box 5: 8)
- "Noch' v shalashe, Nina Vilenkina, 1999 (Box 5: 9)
- "Treugol'nik velikikh derzhav:SSHA, SSSR i Kitai," v. Poremskii, 1981 (Box 5: 10)
- " Rovesnik sovetskoi vlasti,"Aleksandr Spirkin, 1997 (Box 5: 11)
- "V restorane muzyka igrala,Tat'iana Petrosian, 1996 (Box 5: 12)
- "Analiz frantsuzskogo vodevil'nogo repertuara na stsene Mikhailovskikh teatrov v 1830-1840 godakh," Svetlana Bukyzhkina, circa 1990 (Box 5: 13)
- "Russkaia emigratsiia v Khorvatii," Rostislav Polchaninov, 1998 (Box 5: 14)
- "Cstrechi," biulleten' sviazi zarubezhnoi i rossiiskoi organizatsii NTS, 2001 (Box 5: 15)
- "Ischezli iunye zabavy ili strasti vokrug odnogo stikhotvoreniia, " Iurii Druzhnikov, circa 1990 (Box 5: 17)
- "Belochka," Aleksandr Novyi, circa 1990 (Box 5: 17)
- "Loskutki," Larisa Kobrinskaia, 1999 (Box 5: 18)
- "Deviat' iaponskikh miniatiur," Tat'iana Michurina, circa 1990 (Box 5: 19)
- "Stremitel'nyi pokoi," Viktor Krotov, circa 1990 (Box 5: 20)
- "Den' Pobedy," Georgii Avisov, circa 2000 (Box 5: 21)
- "Voennaia byl'," izdanie kadetskogo ob"edineniia, no. 40, 1960 (Box 5: 22)
- "Evrei, armiane, chechentsy-nevol'nye tovarishchi po neschast'iu," Nadezhda Banchik, 1998 (Box 5: 23)
- "V nem krotost' i moshch'," Svetlana Smelianskaia, circa 1990 (Box 5: 24)
- "Vygruzka, kak i pogruzka, predstoit dolgoi," Aleksandr Sibilev, circa 1990 (Box 5: 25)
- "I po venam iz serdtsa ukhodit liubov'," Erik Batuev, 2000 (Box 5: 26)
- "Abkhazskii bereg," Erik Batuev, circa 2000 (Box 5: 27)
- "V perekreshchen'iakh neba i zemli," Leonid Vysheslavskii, 2001 (Box 5: 28)
- "Lara," George Gordon Byron, translated by Marina Zolotarevskaia, 1999 (Box 5: 29)
- "Vremena goda," Anatolii Iukhimenko, circa 1990 (Box 5: 30)
- "Sibirskaia tetrad'," Ida Dubovtseva, 2000 (Box 5: 31)
- "Rotnyi," Nikolai Cherkashin, circa 1955 (Box 5: 32)
- ""Grani," Natal'ia Tarasova, Andrei Svetlanin, circa 1966 (Box 5: 33)
- "Vozvrashchenie poeta," Lev Ozerov, 5: 34 (Box 5: 34)
- "Ia naidu sebe svoe prekrasnoe," Gennadii Kaganovskii, 1998 (Box 6: 1)
- "Zver'," Igor' Kisilev, circa 1990 (Box 6: 2)
- "Sem'ia na odin sezon," Alekssandr Golovkov, circa 1990 (Box 6: 3)
- "Podvodnyi okhotnik," Boris Vul'fovich, 1998 (Box 6: 4)
- "Zasokhshee derevo," Liudmila Sapova, circa1995 (Box 6: 5)
- "Svetloi pamiati Agnii Rzhevskoi," Valentin Senkevich, 1998 (Box 6: 6)
- "Grust' mira poruchena stikham," Elena Dubrovina, 1996 (Box 6: 7)
- "Ne putat' s Dominikanskoi respublikoi," Dar'ia Valikova, circa 1970 (Box 6: 8)
- "Segei Babaian-poslednii realist?" Boris Sokolov, circa 1970 (Box 6: 9)
- " Muzyka zemnogo sostradiia," Svetlana Solozhenkina, circa 1970 (Box 6: 10)
- "Retseptsiia tvorchestva Aleksadra Pushkina v stranakh Baltii," Sergei Isakov, circa 1995 (Box 6: 11)
- "Istoriia pravoslavnoi obshchiny vo Vneshnei Mongolii," Dionisii Pozdniaev, circa 2000 (Box 6: 12)
- "Nasledie Sakharova," Nikita Moravskii, circa 2000 (Box 6: 13)
- "Americanskii klassik Washigton Irving," Valentina Senkevich, circa 2000 (Box 6: 14)
- "Amoral'nye pritchi," Nag Sternin, circa 2000 (Box 6: 15)
- "Chao, bambinochka," Nag Sternin, circa 2000 (Box 6: 16)
- "Poet-romantik, otets detektivnogo romana Edgar Poe," Valentina Senkevich, circa 2000 (Box 6: 17)
- Walt Wiitman-prvyi natsional'nyi poet Ameriki," Valentina Senkevich, circa 2000 (Box 6: 18)
- "Za zakrytymi dveriami," Vladimir Chislenskii, 1997 (Box 6 :19)
- "Provintsial'naia stolitsa," Vladimir Chislenskii, 1996 (Box 6: 20)
- "Pesni autsidera," Vsevolod Emelin, 1991-1999 (Box 6: 21)
- "Tsvetochki iz liubovnogo gerbariia," Evgenii Danilov, circa 2000 (Box 6: 22)
- "Smenivshaia professiiu," Vugar Damirbeili, 1998 (Box 6: 23)
- "Pepel'nye zvezdy," Nikolai Ianev, 1994 (Box 6: 24)
- "Magazin," Aleksei Ivin, 1995 (Box 6: 25)
- "Iuda," Iurii Linnik, circa 1990 (Box 6: 26)
- "Urok sektovedeniia," Aleksandr Nezhnyi, circa 1995 (Box 6: 27)
- "Iz vospominanii,"Vladimir Batshev and Iurii Timofeev, circa 1995 (Box 6: 28)
- "Khoroshee slovo o kommunisticheskom internatsionalizme," Andrei Novikov, circa 1990 (Box 6: 29)
- "Nochnoi disput v masterskoi Voloshina ili tragediia russkoi poezii," Giv Lakhuti, 1996 (Box 6: 30)
- "Golos s drugogo berega," Boris Sokolov, circa 1995 (Box 6: 31)
- "Ottsovskie sapogi," Dmitrii Sergeev, 1990 (Box 6: 32)
- "Otkrytoe pis'mo," Aleksandr Best, circa 1990 (Box 6: 33)
- "Molitva," Mark Kabakov, 1997 (Box 6: 34)
- "Poema shipiashchikh," Natal'ia Fedorova, 1992-1997 (Box 6: 35)
- "Skazka pro gvozdia, vershitelia ustoev," Kirill Ivanovich Svechkin, circa 1990 (Box 6: 36)
- "Krest," Nina Gracheva, 1997 (Box 6: 37)
- Stikhi, Margarita Kuchukova, 1994-1996 (Box 6: 38)
- "Protiv pravil?" Ales' Adamovich, circa 1990 (Box 6: 39)
- "Velikiilekar' velikoi zari," uknown author, 1997 (Box 7: 1)
- "Mir dlia durakov," Vladimir Gurvich, circa 1995 (Box 7: 2)
- "Zhertva, "Mikhail Chernolusskii, 1997 (Box 7: 3)
- "Telefon v Moskve," Gennadii Avilov, 2000 (Box 7: 4)
- "Vozrast," Marina Tumanova, circa 1995 (Box 7: 5)
- "Pamiati B. Chichibabina," Aleksandr Radkovskii, 1993 (Box 7: 6)
- "Olen'ka," Stanislav Alov, circa 2000 (Box 7: 7)
- "Poslednii shedevr," Stanislav Alov, circa 2000 (Box 7: 8)
- "Tri molnii," Aleksandr Novyi, circa 2000 (Box 7: 9)
- "Ispoved'," Vadim Zelikovskii, circa 2000 (Box 7: 10)
- "V starom dome," Dmitrii Sergeev, 1964 (Box 7: 11)
- "Nedolgoe Vot'kino schast'e," Dmitrii Sergeev, 1988 (Box 7: 12)
- "Nitsche i Ril'ke v Rossii. Razmyshleniia filosofa i psikhopata," Evgenii Chernosvitov, 1997 (Box 7: 13)
- "Vokrug chainogo dereva," Vladimir Skrebnitskii, circa 1995 (Box 7: 14)
- "Summa ideologiae," Irina Rodnianskaia, circa 1990 (Box 7: 15)
- "Ne sotvori sebe kumira," Vladimir Shtepa, 1977 (Box 7: 16)
- "Tanki prorvalis' " Vladimir Samarin, circa 1990 (Box 7: 17)
- "Zapret na professiiu cherez VAK," Iu. Manzhura, circa 1985 (Box 8 :1)
- "Nemnozhko o poetakh," V. Turik, undated (Box 8: 2)
- "Stupeni," A. Raiges, 1964 (Box 8: 3)
- Stikhi, Aleksandra Rozenshil'd-Paulin, undated (Box 8: 4)
- "Stony vetra," N. Mashkovskaia, 1947 (Box 8: 5)
- "Pis'mo Viltoru Lavrovu i Galine Ruch'evoi," Leonid Leshchinskii, circa 1980 (Box 8: 6)
- "O russkoi idee," Sergei Utekhin, circa 2000 (Box 8: 7)
- "Zona lagpunkta Mostovitsa Arkhangel'skoi oblasti," Aleksandr Gladkov, 1949-1950 (Box 8: 8)
- "Oskolki zerkala," Marina Tarkovskaia, circa 1995 (Box 8: 9)
- "Bol'shoi poker 1941 goda," Aleksandr Gorianin, circa 2000 (Box 8: 10)
- "Iz detstva," Mikhail Chernolusskii, circa 2000 (Box 8: 11)
- "Pesnia nad Insbrukom," Geogii Avisov, circa 2000 (Box 8: 12)
- "Vechnaia muzyka mira," Boris Chichibabin, 2000 (Box 8: 13)
- "Avgust," Svetlana Tysiachnaia, circa 1990 (Box 8: 14)
- "Moi dom," Elena Bobko, 1987-1994 (Binder 8: 15)
- "Srublennoe derevo, " Vladimir Korobov, circa 1990 (Box 8: 16)
- "Psalmy Davida", 1997 (Box 8: 17)
- "V pustuiu voronku smysla," Arkadii Bartov, circa 1980 (Box 8: 18)
- "Vremia babochek," Nikolai Sokolov, 1999 (Box 8: 19)
- "Uchitel', " Levon Khechoian, circa 1980 (Box 8: 20)
- "Ubiistvo v grafstve Kent," Arkadii Bartov, circa 1990 (Box 8: 21)
- "Fruktovyi sad," Tat'iana Michurina, 1958 (Box 8: 22)
- "Dostoinoe zerno," Svetlana Solozhenkina, 2000 (Box 8: 23)
- "Kachalas' noch' sviataia," Vadim Zelikovskii, circa 1990 (Box 8: 24)
- "Belyi sneg-lebedinaia staia," Larisa Kobrinskaia, 1970-1999 (Box 8: 25)
- "Po sledam russkikh v Severnoi Kalifornii," Alla Avisova, 1999 (Box 8: 26)
- "O nostal'gii, nadezhnosti i ob eliksire nadezhdy," Inna Bogachinskaia, circa 1990 (Box 8: 27)
- "Kazhdyi mig kak podarok," Nikolai Panchenko, circa 1990 (Box 8: 29, Box 8: 28)
- Stikhi, Voktoriia Dobrynina, circa 1980 (Box 8: 30, Box 8: 29)
- "Cherta osedlosti," Evgenii Sykharev, circa 1995 (Box 8: 30)
- "Padaet sneg," Irina Vatyl', circa 1990 (Box 8: 31)
- Stikhi, Vladimir Guzenkov, 2001 (Box 8: 32)
- "Leonidy-sputniku pervykh stranstvii," Tat'iana Kandaurova-Chernysheva, circa 1990 (Box 8: 34, Box 8: 33)
- "Mama, Ia zhiv-zdorov! Vce khorosho," Anatolii Kuznetsov, circa 1990 (Box 8: 34)
- "Pol'sha kak kliuch v rosiiskoi politike v Evrope," Boris Sokolov, circa 1990 (Box 8: 35)
- "Sviatoi," Mark Popovskii, circa 1990 (Box 8: 36)
- "Dlinnaia, zelenaia," Nag Sternin, circa 1990 (Box 8: 37)
- "Poet i smert'," Nataliia Garnits, circa 1980 (Box 8: 38)
- "Diuzhina nozhei v spinu novoi revoliutsii," Andrei Kuchaev, circa 1995 (Box 8: 39)
- "Mne tut teplo," Mark Popovskii, circa 1990 (Box 8: 40)
- "Khudozhnik Nataliia Bragina," Nadezhda Kataeva-Lytkina, 1999 (Box 8: 41)
- "Taina gibeli linkora Imperatritsa Mariia," Lev Viatkin, circa 1990 (Box 8: 42)
- "Glazami segodniashnimi i vcherashnimi," Lev Levitskii, 1990 (Box 8: 43)
- "Bog ostavit tainu-pamiat' obo mne," Ivan Bunin-Leonidu Rzhevskomu, 1954 (Box 8: 44)
- "Kak pervuiu liubov' " Aleksandr Gorianin, circa 1999 (Box 8: 45)
- "De uire Ia svobodnyi chelovek," Grigorii Pas'ko, circa 1990 (Box 9: 1)
- "Tretii Rim: Izvrashchenie Khrista," Vladimir Tsukanilikhin, circa 2000 (Box 9: 2)
- "Mir Dzheka Londona," Valentina Sinkevich, circa 2000 (Box 9: 3)
- "Dnevnik pisatelia," Boris Zaitsev, 1929 (Box 9: 4)
- "Taina vekov," Lev Viatkin, circa 1990 (Box 9: 5)
- "V nashem dome na Angliiskoi naberezhnoi," Nina Lindes, circa 1970 (Box 9: 6)
- "Vospominan'e ob oranzhevykh abazhurakh," Iurii Levitanskii, circa 1995 (Box 9: 7)
- "Kto otravil Napoleona?" Lev Viatkin, circa 1990 (Box 9: 8)
- "Strana, vypavshaia iz vremeni," Vladimir Gurvich, circa 1990 (Box 9: 9)
- "Anatomiia odnogo mifa, " Nag Sternin, circa 1990 (Box 9: 10)
- "Devushka bez adresa," Dar'ia Gushchina, circa 1990 (Box 9: 11)
- "Liki ideokratii," Oleg Vorob'ev, 2000 (Box 9: 12)
- "Pravye i edinstvo Rossii," Nikolai Berdiaev, 1916 (Box 9: 13)
- "Dogorela svecha, dogorela (roman-donos)," Gelii Snegirev, circa 1990 (Box 9: 14)
- "Dozhd'," Levon Khechoian, circa 1995 (Box 9: 15)
- "Posledniaia liubov' v poezii Borisa Pasternaka," Boris Mansurov, circa 2000 (Box 9: 16)
- Stikhi, Valerii Gavrilenko, 1997-1998 (Box 9: 17)
- "Savva," Aleksandra Gol'shtein, circa 1930 (Box 9: 18)
- "Stikhi iz kukol'nykh golov," Platon Nabokov, undated (Box 9: 19)
- "mify o Rossii i dukh natsii," Aleksandr Gorianin, circa 1995 (Box 9: 20)
- "Masimilian Voloshin-uchenik Rudol'fa Shteinera," Vladimir Kupchenko, circa 1990 (Binder 9: 21)
- "Mysli o budushchem strany," beseda Borisa Pushkareva s L'vom Nussbergom, circa 1990 (Box 9: 22)
- "Istoriia grazhdanskoi voiny," Nataliia Bragina, 1988 (Box 9: 23)
- "Dovlatov (plius-minus mif)," Asia Pekurovskaia, 1996 (Box 9: 24)
- "Svet vsepobezhdaiushchei liubvi,' Aleksandr Sibilev, circa 1990 (Box 9: 25)
- "Mrachnyi pisatel' " Nataniel Gotorn," Valentina sinkevich, circa 2000 (Box 9: 26)
- "Mrak i svet Homo Sapiensa," Viktor Togo, 1998 (Box 9: 27)
- "Pamiati Aleksandra Borisovicha Iaroslavskogo (1891-1930)", circa 1990 (Box 9: 28)
- "Palomnichestvo k sviatym mestam Palestiny pravoslavnykh rossiian," Boris Rozenfel'd, circa 1980 (Box 9: 29)
- "Svet ikh druzhby," Anna Toom, circa 2000 (Box 9: 30)
- "O "russkoi idee"," Sergei Utekhin, circa 2000 (Box 9: 31)
- "V zareve legend," Lev Levitskii, 1990 (Box 10: 1)
- "K 80-letiiu Leona Tooma," Anna Toom, 2001 (Box 10: 2)
- "Triptikh," Svetlana Solozhenkina, circa 1998 (Box 10: 3)
- "Polkovnik Elizar," Dmitrii Shliapontokh, circa 2000 (Box 10: 4)
- "Noch' dlinnykh nozhei," Naum Korzhavin, circa 1990 (Box 10: 5)
- "Urok sektovedeniia," Aleksandr Nezhnyi, circa 2000 (Box 10: 6)
- "Proshloe i problemy russkogo protestanizma," Tat'iana Nikol'skaia, circa 2000 (Box 10: 7)
- Stikhi, Anna, 1997-2000 (Box 10: 8)
- "Khorvatiia/Rossiia," Rostislav Polchaninov, 1999 (Box 10: 9)
- "V kontse voiny," Dmitrii Sergeev, 1966 (Box 10: 10)
- "Nevesta byka," Svetlana Morozova, 2002 (Box 10: 11)
- "Poezdka B. B. Martino v Finliandiiu v 1930 g.,: Rostislav Polchaninov, 2000 (Box 10: 12)
- "Russkaia enigraysiia v Khorvatii, " Rostislav Polchaninov, circa 2000 (Box 10: 13)
- "A. A. Kornilov "Preobrazhenie Rossii," Rostislav Polchaninov, 2000 (Box 10: 14)
- "Nasha igra v soldatiki, " Rostislav Polchaninov, circa 2000 (Box 10: 15)
- "Russkii kommisar," Lev Viatkin, circa 1995 (Box 10: 16)
- "Mikhail Bulgakov i Gustav Mei rink," Aleksandr Vladimirskii, circa 1995 (Box 10: 17)
- "Man'ka," Vladimir Korobov, circa 1995 (Box 10: 18)
- "Datskii korol' v lesakh Latvii," Anna Kurt, 1997 (Box 10: 19)
- Stikhi, Vladimir Korobov, circa 1990 (Box 10: 20)
- "Glavy iz romana "Izgoi ," Viktor Petrov, circa 1995 (Box 10: 21)
- "Predely svobody," Andrei Novikov, circa 1995 (Box 10: 22)
- "Kitaets," Vladimir Korobov, circa 1995 (Box 10: 23)